it is a story as old as time itself a
new Trader will jump into day trading
expecting to get rich overnight without
having any prior knowledge about trading
just to watch their account dwindle away
and possibly even blow their account all
together as a beginner day trading is
one of the most dangerous things you can
do and in this video what I'm going to
do is break down why that is the case
and three options that you have that
will nearly guarantee that you avoid
that disastrous situation and turn day
trading into a source of income so if
that sounds good go ahead and click that
like button for me go ahead and
subscribe if you are new and I'll be
right back after the intro and
[Music]
disclaimer welcome back let's go ahead
and get started first off I'm going to
explain the main four reasons that day
trading is a disaster for 95% of
beginners then I'm going to move on to
three options that you have that will
help you make day trading a source of
income let's talk about the four main
reasons that that day trading is a
disaster for beginners first reason
number one if you are a complete
beginner then you likely don't have a
trading plan and frankly with no
disrespect you don't know how to trade
yet and what tends to happen if you
don't know how to do something are you
normally good at something you don't
know how to do no not at all so if you
don't have the skill necessary to trade
if you don't have a completed trading
plan then starting to day trade is going
to destroy your trading account because
you're going to be trading based on
emotions like fear and greed instead of
trading based on a statistic advantage
that gives you an edge over the market
over time and this not knowing how to
trade leads me into the next reason that
day trading can be a disaster for
beginners and reason number two is that
day trading comes with a high frequency
of Trades so let's put these two
together if you're brand new to trading
you don't really know what you're doing
you don't know how to trade you don't
have a proven trading plan and then you
trade more what's going to happen you're
going to lose money faster because the
frequency of Trades on Lower time frames
like day trading you're going to have
more trades so it's just going to give
you the opportunity to lose money a lot
faster and that actually leads really
well into reason number three day
trading is a disaster for beginners
which is that beginners including myself
when I first started tend to look at
trading as a getrich quick idea and in
order to get rich fast they tend to know
that they have to risk a lot of money
per trade so what that means is that
beginners normally have a lack of risk
management this lack of risk management
combined with a high frequency of Trades
combined with the fact that you don't
have a proven trading plan if you are a
complete beginner can make day trading
an absolute disaster for you if you are
just starting out and reason number four
is just the simple fact that you likely
don't have time to dedicate to day
trading in order to day trade you would
normally need to schedule out a block of
time between 4 to8 hours that you are
actually trading and these hours need to
be when the market has volatility that
most of the time is during the New York
session or the London session now as a
beginner for the most part I know I did
most of us as beginners have a full-time
job that we do or at least a part-time
job that we have to show up to so with
this being the case you will either have
to sacrifice your job that's maintaining
your livelihood or sacrifice sleep in
order to have a proper schedule for day
trading and that's just not realistic
for most beginners before we talk about
the three options you have that will
help you make money as a day trader
first I want to make this very clear I
am not against day trading whatsoever
once you get good at trading day trading
can be extremely profitable but the key
part of that sentence is once you get
good at trading if you don't know what
you're doing and you try to day trade
that's when it can be a disaster if you
know what you're doing you already have
a profitable trading plan and you day
trade the higher frequency of Trades
that comes with can help you make a lot
more money than you can doing something
like swing trading or long-term ter
investing so with that being the case
let's go ahead and talk about three
options you have that can help you make
money as a day trader option numeral Uno
is to create a full trading plan based
around day trading by learning or
creating a strategy or strategies that
you can use in the market so let's talk
about the steps you need to take in
order to create a full trading plan
around day trading first off you will
need to create a trading schedule again
in order to day trade you're going to
need to have a block of time between 4
and 8 hours where you can stay behind
your computer and the block of time
normally needs to be when markets are
most volatile either in the New York or
London session next inside of this
trading plan you will need to have the
rules for the trading system or trading
systems that you've decided to create or
learn from someone else and I'm going to
go over this a little more once we get
through all four steps of creating your
own trading plan around day trading I'm
going to talk to you a little bit about
how to create your own trading system
but let's continue with this on step
number three and you heard it here first
back test the out of your TR
trading system what I mean by that is
once you've created this trading system
or even if it's a system that you've
learned from someone else you need to
take the rules for that system and back
test them this simply means you need to
go back in historic data and look for
every time on a specific currency pair
and whatever specific time frame you've
chose to trade on you need to look for
every time the rules for the system you
are going to be trading have happened
you need to do this a lot you need to do
this at least 100 times per pair and per
time frame that you're planning to trade
with this specific strategy if you're
trading stocks you need do this a 100
times per stock and per time frame that
you're planning to trade this system on
this process of back testing not only
ensures that we're trading something
that's at least been profitable in the
past and is likely to be profitable in
the future but also helps us with our
trading psychology and helps us to
understand the system and the strategy
that we're trading by showing us this
system going in and out of draw Downs
going in and out of losing streaks and
still coming out ahead on the other side
of that after a large sample size of
Trades and lastly number four is to
create a reasonable risk management plan
if you take these four steps you will
have created your own trading plan for
day trading and after doing so then you
can demo trade this trading plan and at
some point after being profitable in
demo trading let's say you decide to
demo trade for a month to see if it's
profitable and you are profitable for
that month then you can decide if you
want to open up a live account and
actually trade this full system but
doing this is going to prepare you for
day trading whereas when you are a
complete beginner without doing any of
this work you are just gambling you are
trading based on emotion based on fear
and greed based on something someone
else said when you do this when you take
these steps and create your own full
trading plan around day trading you are
putting in the work and that work will
pay off now let's go ahead and talk
about how to create your own system when
it comes to learning a system in order
to do this all you have to do is go on
YouTube or go to whoever your Mentor is
find out the system they use and make
sure it's rules rules based if it is
rules based you can take that exact
system or multiple systems and back test
those systems and then create a trading
plan around them but if you want to
create one yourself here's the process
that I personally use to create trading
systems I call this process CEST
c s and what this stands for is
conditions an actual entry reason where
am I going to have my stop- loss and
where am I going to have my Target and
let me break down each of these really
quickly condition
would be things like the Market's in
Trend or at a level of structure or any
specific indicators you want to use
let's say the RSI is oversold the RSI
has Divergence there's a higher time
frame level of structure the trend on
the higher time frame is aligning with
my trading time frame conditions are
infinite you can have any number of
conditions when you are creating a
trading system next up we have entries
for me what I use as entries 95% of the
time is either chart patterns like
double tops and double bottoms Head and
Shoulder patterns or Candlestick
patterns like engulfing pattern or
something like a hammer or a shooting
star candle combining these conditions
with this entry is what gives us our
actual reason to press the buy or sell
button but we're not done yet after
we've created conditions and entry we
need to know where we're getting out if
the market does not cooperate with our
analysis trading is not about being
right 100% of the time it's about
managing risk understanding our system
and having a system that actually gives
us an edge over a large sample size of
Trades so having a stop loss is
imperative with that being the case so
we need to know where we're getting out
if we're wrong and lastly we need to at
least have an idea of where we're going
to get out if we're actually right so
that is option number one and that is
the process of creating a full system if
that's the route you want to take or you
can just learn a system from someone
else with that being said we have plenty
of strategies and systems based on the
CES model available here on our Channel
along with inside of the TTC Forex
University which is our VIP mentorship
program so if you want a little bit more
of a mentorship and more guidance on
becoming a profitable day trader feel
free to check that out it's going to be
the top Link in the description or go to
www.th trading channel.com and for those
of you who stay till the end of the
video I'll be sharing a full rules-based
day trading strategy with you so stick
around for that and now let's move on to
option number two this option is for
those of you who are like I'm not
interested in developing a trading
strategy myself or learning a
rules-based trading strategy from
someone else and option number two is
for you to create a full discretionary
trading plan around day trading and demo
trade that until you're profitable now
discretionary trading is much more
subjective which means it's not based on
a specific set of rules a discretionary
trading approach would be you looking at
a chart and going hey based on what I
see on this chart I'm expecting price to
do this but you're doing it without any
rules and if that's the path you want to
follow let me go ahead and tell you it
is much more difficult to follow that
path than it is to adopt a rules-based
trading system or create a rules-based
trading system but it is doable and
here's the path you would need to take
and the steps you would need to take to
accomplish a discretionary trading plan
built around day trading number one is
still the same you still need a schedule
where you're behind your computer at the
same time every single day and you're
planning to day trade during that block
of time between 4 and 8 hours number two
is that you're going to have a
discretionary trading approach you need
to study the out of techn analysis
so you completely understand Trend
structure patterns indicators whatever
it is you're going to be trading based
around you need a very clear
understanding of those things next you
still need a reasonable risk management
plan when you're taking this approach
and finally the fourth step in this is
to demo trade the out of your
discretionary trading approach after a
10-year trading career if I was starting
and wanted to have a discretionary
approach to day trading what I would do
is just open a demo count immediately
while studying technical analysis and I
would trade in that demo account until I
was profitable consistently for three
months in a row with my day trading and
at that point is when you can decide
whether or not you want to open up a
live account and utilize your
discretionary approach in a live account
don't do it from jump don't do it from
the get-go and just start as a beginner
and go ah I'm going to be good enough at
discretionary trading you're not I
promise I tried that and I'm not telling
you that to like make you feel feel bad
or make it seem like I'm fussing at you
or anything like that I'm just telling
you the truth from my own experience I
thought that when I came into markets
and I got slaughtered because I thought
I could just take a discretionary
trading approach without any practice
and it caused me to blow my first
account and lose a ton of money at the
beginning of my own trading career so
I'm trying to help you avoid that
mistake if you're going to take this
discretionary approach to day trading
make sure that first you can be
consistently profitable with this day
trading approach with this discretionary
approach for at least 3 months straight
in just a second I'll be sharing with
you an entire rules-based trading
strategy that's been profitable for me
for many years so be sure to stick
around for that but for now let's go
over option number three which is simply
to swing trade instead of day trade
swing trading happens on higher time
frames so what this does is annihilate
two out of the four reasons that day
trading is so detrimental for beginners
one of those being the frequency of
Trades while swing trading is going to
be less so even if you jump into markets
and you make mistakes and you're losing
trades while you're swing trading you're
going to be losing less trades because
on higher time frames the frequency of
Trades you get whether that be based on
a discretionary trading approach or
based on a systematic strategy the
frequency of Trades is going to be
smaller so you will lose money less
frequently you will lose money slower so
that kind of annihilates that reason why
day trading is so dangerous for
beginners another thing is the schedule
whenever it comes to day trading finding
the time that's a 4H hour or a 8 Hour
block of time that you can be in front
of your computer can be really difficult
but in swing trading it makes it much
easier to develop a schedule around a
full-time job or other obligations to
give you an example of this the strategy
that I use right now I mainly trade on
4our charts at the moment the strategy I
use right now is extremely similar to
the strategy I used whenever I had a
full-time job including the schedule all
I do is have an alarm for the close of
every 4H hour candle 95% of my trades
the actual reason for entry is the close
of a 4-Hour candle so I just have an
alarm set for every four hours I was
able to accomplish and to utilize this
swing trading strategy even with a
full-time job because of the way swing
trading allows you to build your
schedule so if this is the approach you
want to take let's take a look at the
steps you need to accomplish step number
one one is exactly the same you still
need to schedule but again scheduling
around swing trading much easier than
scheduling around day trading next up
you're going to need either a
discretionary approach to swing trading
or a full system that's rules-based that
beats the market as in it has an edge
over time next up you'll still need to
have a reasonable risk management plan
and another difference between day
trading and swing trading day trading
you have to be patient don't get me
wrong absolutely it is necessary no
matter what time frame you're Trading
for you to be patient but swing trading
requires a bit more patience because
from a swing trading approach it's going
to take longer for trades to happen so
your analysis isn't going to play out
immediately how it seems that it does
while you're day trading also it's going
to take longer for targets or stop-
losses to get hit after you're in a
trade so being patient is extremely
important when it comes to a swing
trading approach and with that said that
is option number three now we are about
to dive into a full rules-based day
trading strategy that was developed
utilizing the C acronym that you learned
early in the video and this strategy is
one that is proven to be profitable for
me for years but before we get into that
if you've enjoyed the video so far be
sure to click that like button for me go
ahead and subscribe if you are new and
again if you're ready for some more
advanced training and you want more of a
mentorship from me personally then feel
free to check out the TTC forx
University by clicking the top Link in
the description or going to
www.th trading channel.com now the
Strate you're about to learn is a day
trading strategy that I've utilized for
years across all markets including Forex
stocks and crypto this is a strategy
from a video I Shot over two years ago
but again it's still just as applicable
and I still use it anytime I want to
trade on Lower time frames I still use
it to this day to day trade with so if
you want to learn the exact systematic
strategy that I use anytime I trade on
Lower time frames then be sure to check
this out and I will see you directly
after for the strategy you're learning
today we're going to align ourselves on
the correct side of the market based
around Trend the specific way we are
going to do that is by utilizing two
time frames our first time frame needs
to be one time frame up from the time
frame we plan to trade on and we're
going to dive into that in just a second
and our second time frame is going to be
the time frame we actually place the
trade on so here on the Aussie Canada
the trade was placed on a 5 minute chart
so what I mean by what I just said is
that where we find the trend of this
Market in order to be on the right side
of the market when we place our trade we
want to be in line with the higher time
frame Trend in order to find that if
we're trading the five minute chart then
I'm going to look one time frame up to
the 15minute Chart now as you can see
right here this is all the time frames
that I use so I always go up one time
frame with this strategy if I'm trading
on the 15minute chart then I'm going up
to the 1 hour if I'm trading on the 1
hour I'm going up to the 4 Hour if I'm
trading on the 4 Hour I'm going up to
the Daily now I rarely go up any higher
than that but that is the exact
difference in time frames that I
personally use so again on this chart
what trend are we in you can tell cuz I
already have it drawn out for you but
this is an obvious downtrend because we
have a starting point right here which
is one of our major swing levels we then
have a major swing level here a major
swing level here and a major swing level
here followed by a lower high major
swing level and a lower low major swing
level this tells me that I'm definitely
in a downtrend I know for a fact I'm in
a downtrend at this point so if I want
to align myself on the right side of the
market based on my higher time frame
Trend then I want to be looking for
short trades so the first step in this
strategy is we are aligning ourselves on
the right side of the market using
higher time frame Trend once a major
swing level is broken that is the level
you want to look at for Trend
continuation so as this Market pulls
back up to this area that's where I want
to look for possible opportunities to
hop on that Trend and ride it to the
downside as you can see this works out
very often if we go back right here to
our previous major swing level yeah I
know I widened that area a bit but these
are zones not just lines on a chart you
can see that this is exactly where the
Market pulled back to before pushing
down and breaking another major swing
level so we're expecting that to
continuously happen until the market
shows us it doesn't want to do that
anymore by breaking through this major
swing level our resistance level and
creating a possible reversal so with all
that being the case after identifying my
Trend and identifying the previous major
swing level that was broken on my higher
time frame and in this case that is the
the 15minute chart because I'm planning
to trade on the 5 minute chart the next
thing I do is extremely simple I just
drop down to that five minute chart I'll
wait on the market asset whatever it is
I'm trading I'll wait on it to come back
up into this area and then I want to see
rejection and I have very specific rules
for that rejection too I'm not going to
leave you hanging on the entry reason
don't worry the whole point of all this
by the way is to make sure we have
what did we say at the beginning if
you're going to be a successful day
trader if you want to make money from
day trading you need a strategy that's
rules-based so you can stay consistent
to it and it's proven to make money over
time this is a strategy I've used for
nearly a decade and it's proven to make
money for me during that time and it's
also so rules based that you can stay
consistent to it one rule is higher time
frame Trend let's align ourselves with
that second rule look for the last major
swing level that was broken the third
rule is is rejection and the way we're
looking for rejection is by looking for
the market to create a high come to that
high and then be rejected from it by
pushing lower this is known as a double
top and it's extremely simple price
pattern that I use for entry reasons now
one small caveat I do have is that after
this double top I want to see a red
candle so we have a test we have our
second test of a resistance level and
then I want to see a red candle here for
the push down you will see that on the
chart for this trade right now okay so
here we have the market exactly where it
was whenever I entered this trade
everything's lining up about the rules
we just discussed we're in line with our
higher time frame Trend we're at the
previous major swing level that was
broken what did I say I was looking for
well as you can see is as we push up
here we get a high but then the Market's
not ready to continue lower because why
we break through that high and make a
higher high so at this point I'm not
interested in going short and trying to
ride this trend down until I get actual
confirmation and do we get it here as we
push back up no we get a move up that
ends up closing above our previous High
we get no rejection at this level so
what I'm waiting for is when this Market
is pushed
down we get a push back up to that same
level and then we see rejection
rejection being this red candle right
here and my exact rules for this I'll go
ahead and share them with you is that
for a double top I am looking for the
market to push up and get between the
high of the wick and the highest bodies
of this entire little area and I'll
explain that in just a second whenever I
get this a little bit darker for you so
this is my area it's between the highest
bodies of this previous swing High and
the highest Wick of this previous swing
High what I want to see is Wicks of
candles touching this area bodies of
candles can close in this area the only
thing that cannot happen is I do not
want to see a close above here because
that's exactly what's been happening
right that's not showing rejection close
above close above what I want to see is
rejection so a wick needs to get into
this zone or a body needs to get into
this zone of a candle and then I want to
see a red candle showing me that sellers
are trying to take control when you
combine all of that and you have your
alignment with a higher time frame Trend
you have the market inside of a major
swing level the previous one that was
broken that is Major structure and
that's one of the most likely places for
a market to continue in Trend and you
add all of that to an objective entry
reason as powerful as a double top with
selling pressure afterwards that being
that red candle then what it creates is
a consistent way of trading because
there's rules for every bit of it so
that that equals consistence right and
it creates a money-making Edge played
out over a large sample size at least
from my own point of view and my own
trading that I have done with this
strategy it has been one of the best
I've discovered in the past 10 years I
think it took like an hour or so for
this whole trade to play out and hit
about a 2.4 to1 reward to risk ratio but
this is a bearish version of the
strategy hopefully that was extremely
clear but just to clear things up a
little bit further and to give you an
example of a bullish version of this
what we're going to do now is go to a
different chart and take a look at a
bullish version of this strategy I'll
see you there so remember when I was
saying that this works on all different
markets and in all different time frames
right now we're going to be looking for
a trade on the 15-minute chart so what
time frame will I be looking at if
that's the case for my Trend
identification to make sure I'm on the
right side of the market with this trade
if I'm trading on the 15 minute I want
to look up at the 1eh hour chart for my
Trend identification and that major
swing level that was broken last just to
be sure that you understand this because
it is a pivotal part of your trading
career to understand major swing levels
and how to draw out a trend it will play
a vital part in nearly any strategy that
you try to trade or if you're just
someone that is going to trade with a
discretionary approach you need to
understand how to identify Trends so
from this being our starting point we
have a push up to a major swing High
pull back to a major swing low push up
to a major swing High pull back to a
major swing low push up where do we
break this level and remember feel
free no way that's going to work
remember feel free to put horizontal
lines at your major swing levels so at
this point we know that this would be
our major swing level if we had more of
a pullback really it's right here again
no way to make this completely objective
it just depends on how you see the
market from here I would go to here then
move my horizontal line up we have a
major swing level that's broken here so
now we would have this move to a major
swing level back down to a equal low for
our major swing level back up now where
do we break
here right over here right since we
broke right here that means that I'm now
looking at this as my next major swing
level this is my next major swing low
major swing high if we move the chart
forward now and I click the button one
time you'll see that we have this
pullback so what what are we doing we're
in an uptrend which direction do we want
to trade to the upside right what do we
need to point out we need to point out
and draw a Zone near our last level of
resistance our last major swing level
which is these two right here I'm
combining them here because they are so
close together height-wise since they're
both really really close to around the
$278 Mark I'm just putting that in the
middle of the Zone this is just how
you'll have to draw out zones they're
not lines on a chart support and
resistance are a lot more like zones so
in this case we have our area that we're
looking at the previously broken major
swing level again we're just splitting
the difference between these two because
they're so close together and we have
the market in this area what's the next
step at this point we want to drop down
to our actual trading time frame which
is going to be the 15minute chart in
this case and now we can actually look
for what are we looking for if we're
looking for a bullish trade it's not
going to be a double top right we're
going to be looking for a double bottom
in this case
so there we have a push up what we need
to see is the market come down and now
reject this area here somehow some way
it needs to come down and show us
rejection of that and the way we do that
is just by candles getting into that
zone whether that be by Wicks or by
candle bodies themselves and then a
green candle to show us buying pressure
out of it so if we keep pushing forward
we're in the zone and now we're still in
the zone and boom we now have a green
candle this would be our actual entry
the close of that candle slash the open
of the next candle would be the entry
for me and the way I trade this after
that I would just have a stop loss below
the lowest low of the rejection of the
double bottom after I had my stop loss
placed my target would be back up at the
previous resistance level right over
here and I would probably pick this one
just because it's slightly lower than
the other so let's do that still set up
with a 2. 3 to1 reward to risk ratio
here on Litecoin and let's see how this
plays
out as you can see the market takes off
to the upside easily hitting our targets
so that's a bullish version of this
strategy so now let's dive into a recap
of everything here on the chart of
Microsoft as I said Works in all
different markets and on all different
time frames we're looking at the 4H hour
chart after this I have something
extremely important to share with those
of you who are actually serious about
starting a day trading career so look
forward to that after we go through this
recap right now let's recap what we've
already learned let's use every bit of
that strategy here on Microsoft so on
Microsoft we start from a starting point
that is right down here we have a push
up to a major swing High a pullback to a
major swing low a push up a pullback
we're just drawing it out again as a
recap and to make sure you completely
understand this pull back to here when
do we break Above This high right here
okay so we break above the high we have
another pullback and this pullback then
creates a new high for another major
swing level at this point what's the
trend on our 4our chart we're going to
be trading on the 1 hour so we just went
up one time frame on our 4our chart we
are in an uptrend while we're in this
uptrend what is the latest major swing
level that we broke it is right here
this is the latest major swing level
according to the rules of our trading
strategy that we've broken now we have a
pull back into that level let's drop
down to a smaller time frame if we're
looking for the higher time frame Trend
and structure on the 4H hour that means
we're trading on the one hour again as I
explained earlier and since this is a
recap I'll go over everything so if
you're on the 5 minute looking for
trades you look for structure and trend
on 15 if you're on the 1 hour looking
for trades you look for structure and
trend on the 4 Hour and if you're on the
4our looking for trades you're look at
the daily for your Trend and structure
now let's drop down to our trading time
frame what are we looking for here well
in the case of a bullish trade we'd be
looking for a double bottom does this
meet the rules for our double bottom yes
it does we have a push down we have a
bottom we then have a neckline we're
looking for a retest of this area
without closing below it that gives us
buying pressure we then get a green
candle followed by an even bigger green
candle which is where our entry would be
on that buying pressure candle for stop
loss we would go below this low and I
use something called an ATR indicator I
have a full video for that it's up in
the leth hand side of your screen right
hand side of your wherever it's at it's
in the cards you'll be able to see it it
should pop up right now ATR is right up
here and what it shows me is that we
currently have a
$231 ATR it gives you the average
movement of the last 14 candles it's
pretty much what the ATR does to keep
you in line with the volatility of the
market so below our swing low I want to
go down down $231 if our swing low is at
18520 then I want to be at somewhere
around
18289 for my stop loss so 182 89 that's
going to be close enough even though it
says 92 oh my target to be back up at
previous resistance right up here the
previous major swing High then I hit
play we'll see how this plays
out and as you can see eventually coming
up and hitting those targets we did have
a little gap down here but it didn't
even come close to the stop loss so
there is a recap of every part of the
strategy hopefully that was good enough
to get you to a point of completely
understanding the strategy but the
strategy is not all you need look on my
neck right now this is a triangle and
there is a reason that I'm wearing
triangle jewelry today and it's because
I want to share something extremely
important for those of you who are
serious about your trading this is
something you must master and that is
the triangle of trading success so the
triangle of trading success if you have
not heard of it is three skills that you
must have in order to make money in any
Financial Market if you're a day trader
swing Trader long-term investor it does
not matter everyone that makes money
trading in financial markets has these
three skills mastered the first one is
exactly what we went over today they
have a strategy that they can stay
consistent to and that makes money over
time this is a huge part of trading
success but it's not everything in any
way shape or form you also must have a
risk management plan that keeps you out
of your emotions and initially keeps you
from blowing your account the strategy
we just looked at is a strategy that
wins somewhere around it's a little bit
less than 50 but somewhere around 50% of
the time and has a 2: one reward to risk
ratio this provides me with an edge this
provides me with a money-making strategy
over long periods of time but if I risk
my entire account value on my first
trade then I have a it's gambling I have
a 50/50 chance of losing that's why we
need a risk management plan in place
that keeps us in the market long enough
gives us chips and a chair at a poker
table in order to let this Edge play out
because otherwise we're just gambling so
the important part of this is to be sure
that initially our risk management plan
keeps us from really having the chance
to blow an account there's always a
chance but it reduces that chance by
99% and the second part of a risk
management plan is to keep you out of
your emotions to keep fear and greed
from controlling your decisions while
you're placing trades in any Financial
Market the way we keep that fear and
greed from controlling us is by making
the amount we lose per trade being small
enough for us to be able to handle
because you will lose trades I have
losing trades you will have losing
trades but the important part is not to
let them affect you emotionally because
if they affect you emotionally you might
make mistakes that ruin your Edge that
ruin your statistic advantage and that
ruin your money-making strategy and all
of this is irrelevant if you can't find
a way to have good trading psychology or
discipline is what this is also known as
trading psychology it allows you to
stick to that strategy not have fomo not
switch strategies to not just Place
trades because you just got stopped out
of one and now you're going to go super
aggressive and you're going to risk more
than normal because you just lost a
trade you want to try to make that money
back all of that is emotional mistakes
due to having bad trading psychology so
this is something you must absolutely
master in order to create a profitable
trading career that was a little bonus
on the other things you need outside of
a strategy so with that you now have a
full plan to turn day trading into a
source of income and you know the
dangers of starting the day trade as a
complete beginner without first
completing the steps we've talked about
throughout this video if you found that
to be helpful go ahead and click that
like button for me go ahead and
subscribe if you're new we come out with
videos like this each and every week
don't forget if you're interested in
some more advanced training and to be
mentored by me personally go ahead and
click the top Link in the description to
learn more about the TTC Forex
University if you're not interested in
that no big deal at all I wish you the
best of luck on all your future trades I
hope you trade green and I'll talk to
you in the next video see you soon